CHAWIRA CURTHBERT

| ■+263 78 500 14 94 | | M curthbertchawira2016@gmail.com |

COMPUTER ENGINEER

Profile	
• A fully qualified Computer Engineer with experience as IT Support for network, operating systems and	d applicat
at the end user level. I am enthusiastic about developing a career in computer Engineering. My ability to	stay

ions focused under pressure allows me to perform efficiently and with precision in high demand situations. I possess excellent analytical and problem-solving skills with the ability to make independent judgements. I strive to be empathetic, respectful and cooperative in all interactions. I am highly numerate and with a solid mathematical scientific background. With a strong commitment to my personal development and achievement, I endeavor to be resourceful and creative in all my endeavors, bringing a fresh perspective to situations while upholding core company values.

Skil		

Ductio

• C# | .NET | Java | JavaScript | TypeScript | C++ | C | CosmosDB | MSSQL | Node | Express | React | Vue | Redux | jQuery | NoSQL | Git • Microservices | Distributed Systems | Frontend | Backend .

Technical

•Troubleshooting applications, hardware and software, Network security, Dynamic Web design and Developer, Front end and back backend developer,

HTML, CSS and JavaScript, ASP.Net and PHP, SQL, Software installations on desktop and laptops, Data backup

Experience ___

Software Developer

European University of Nicosia, TRNC 06/2016-09/2016 (intern)

- As part of my prerequisite at my university I am allocated 45 days to do my internship training.
- I did my internship at Robotics lab at European University of Lefke
- I worked with Arduino on different projects, I also worked with Raspberry pi
- I also combined Raspberry Pi and Arduino on some projects

Web Developer **Gigabyte Ltd** Nicosia, TRNC 05/2020 - 09/2020

- Worked as part of a development team to implement the use of Flutter and dat.
- Collaborated with the supervisor to successfully debug issues in the GUI for the mobile application.
- Participated in client-based projects to design and implement mobile applications using dart and flutter.
- Collaborated in and participated in designing a UI and implementing the database by migrating a web-based barcode system into a mobile application.
- Worked as part of a team tasked to design, develop and implement an application for small business.
- Developed project spec questionnaire to identify client needs and streamline the project development process by writing the software requirements and the project documentation.

& software Development

- Software Development, website using WordPress, Analyze and resolves service desk support problems
- Provide end user training and support.
- Provide with IT systems support and maintenance on desktops, laptops, server, hardware, work infrastructure communication sytems and carryout end user support.
- Backup of active equipment configuration of the backup equipment

Software Developer MBL Hightech Girne, TRNC 06/2021 - 12/2021

- Participating in daily scrum meetings, sprint planning, unit testing and bug fixes.
- Developing and designing pages and forms using PHP, MYSQL, and CSS for a new marketplace.
- In charge of designing, developing and deploying a hybrid App for a marketplace with ionic react and node.js
- Working with other developers and designers to develop the website and applications.
- Designing, development, deployment, and maintenance of all menu maintenance portal code using PHP, MYSQL, HTML, CSS and JavaScript.

IT Support And Network

Taat Consulting

Harare, Zimbabwe

01/2022 - 11/2022

Administrator

- Support IT approved software for desktop and laptop computers
- Troubleshoot and resolve network communication issues. Configure machines, software, printers and network access.
- Primarily worked alongside a senior mentor, which required maintaining effective communication, ability to learn quickly in order to adapt to an initially unfamiliar environment and enhanced my ability to question and analyses critically.
- Perform intermediate level maintenance and configuration tasks.
- Oversee network security
- Monitor and report on network operations. Maintain routers, switches, hubs, VPN's and servers.
- Plan and design network additions and expansions. Software development and updates
- Responsible for data base management systems, dynamic web development.
- Managing help desk (manage engine service desk plus) application development

Support electrical engineer Pikay Electrical Harare, Zimbabwe 02/2023 - present

- Electrical installation => domestic, industrial and mining.
- High voltage construction (transformer maintenance, substation construction, high voltage underground transmission, line construction and maintenance and cable jointing and maintenance)
- Programming Logic Computer (PLC) Panel wiring
- Installation of water pumps through the use of photovoltaic system
- Design of cable alignment through the use.

Education